Alright guys. I got some good news, and I
got some bad news. So the good news is
we're ready to go ahead with the next
step and make this look a little better.
The bad news is that I was not able to
find any icon fonts that have the
icons that we need. Now the other good
news is we can always use images. So, I'm
going to go ahead and search here on
Google, and you guys can do the same. We
need three or five icons. We need an icon
of a gun, crosshairs, a helmet, something
charge, maybe electricity, and then a
radiation symbol. So I'm going to precede
each one of these searches with the word
icon gun, and I'm just gonna grab this
one right here. I didn't mean to inspect
that. Save image. It's actually under
webstorm projects. There we go. Crosshairs...
and this looks about right. So let's save
this as well. A helmet...
this isn't very helpful. Sorry, just
sneezed there. None of these really look
accurate as to what the image showed, or
the pip-boy, rather. I don't think it's
really necessary, I guess. Let's go ahead
and grab this one.
That's SVG which should be fine. Then we need
energy, so icon charge. And something
like this right here, but that has a
weird kind of overlay on it. I guess they
don't want people taking it, so let's not.
Search for energy...that will do. Save this.
And then the last one is a radiation, or
nuclear, rather. But they should both
turn up the same thing. One of them
should look something like this. But, that's
not a PNG image, so we can't really use
that. Let's go ahead and look at this one.
No, we need a transparent background.
That's one of the one of the things we
do absolutely need. If we can't find one
we can always use one that looks
slightly different, like this. So, save
that image. There we go. Now we've got all
our images so now we need to add them in
here. This of course is the gun. So let me
go ahead in here and label them, maybe I
should have. That one, that one, there we
go.
So in here it was right here, and this is
going to be 2459-200.png
with a class of image-responsive.
Save it and refresh, let's see what we've
got here. Set the width of that to a
hundred percent, and then we're gonna
have to apply filters on it. So filter,
grayscale is one, invert two, brightness two,
let's remove the invert. Just trust on
the brightness adding up. Contrast zero,
that looks a bit better, and then sepia. And then hue
rotate is gonna be 55 degrees, and then
saturate it's gonna be 20. There we go.
Let's have a look at the pip-boy...it looks
just about right. I think that's
as good as I can get it, anyway. So, let's
go ahead and style these up. So in stat-numbers, image, you need these. Save and
refresh, and there we go. Now I can add
the crosshairs one here, so it's right
here. So image, and the crosshairs one was this one I believe, it was. So 27502-200.png
I don't think I need to add a class
there. Save, refresh, and this one needs to
go a bit bigger. So, width, actually...
we need to increase that size quite
a bit. Not that much.
Then we need to margin-left is going
to be -5 pixels. There we go. I'm
going to set this to sm-image so that we
can style that on its own. Save.
Stat-numbers, img.sm-image, I think that's
what I called it.
Alright. Save it and refresh, there we go.
Now we need that helmet which I believe
was the SVG image. Yes, it was.
Alright, so let's close
this. This right here.
I'm totally gonna rename this, it's gonna
make a lot easier, and class image-
responsive. Save and refresh, there we go. Not quite big enough though. Oh, there's
padding around it, that's why. So I'm
gonna set this one to 140
pixels, then we're gonna set margin
left to negative 20 pixels, and set this to zero.
That's totally a negative five, there we
go.
And padding-top is gonna be five pixels
as well. So this is gonna be specific to
the helmet icon, so we need to add a
class here. Save this, jump back over here...
save it and refresh. Awesome, we have two
more icons to do, and then we need to fix
up the numbers, and also the general
position of this. So the energy should be
that right there, and it's going to be kind of the same
story. I think we're gonna need to custom
style that. Let's jump down create image
source icons_energy_managers.png, and
then close that off. Save it and refresh.
We will need to style that, but for right
now let's leave it as is and go ahead
and add the irradiation icon as well. So
I'm just going to drop down in here.
Image source equals radiation icon, and I
love autocomplete specifically for that.
Save and refresh, and there we've got all
our icons in. But now, this whole thing is
looking a bit off-kilter.
What would happen if I removed this one
altogether.
That's a little too...let's set the first one...
spacing. Let's do that. Instead of having
a col-2 at the very
beginning, I'm gonna have a spacer-numbers. Let's save it, and let's give
that an absolute width here. A little more...that looks about right. That looks more
right. So let's say 50 pixels. So spaceer-numbers, that's a really bad name to give
that, but it does what we need it to do,
spacer-numbers be this. And then we need
to move this row up a bit, if we can, and
we should be able to. I'm gonna say
margin-top equals negative 50 pixels.
That looks about right. So this is going
to be stat numbers. There we go. This is
the main page of the pip-boy. It does
have a name down there as well which we
haven't added. And a few things are off,
like this progress bar should be a bit
bigger, and this is something you guys
can play around with. In the next video I
think we're just gonna finish up this
part just by maybe making an inventory
page, and most of the concepts on all the
other pages will inherit from the
inventory, or data page. So I think just
the inventory one will be fine. Thank you
guys for watching, and I'll see you guys
in the next video.