All right guys.
So what we need to do at this point is we actually need to be able to get the you are out of the video.
Now this is where things are going to get a little complicated and unreliable as I'm not sure how often
YouTube is going to change this but for right now their systems are set up in a way that we can grab
the video you are Elle's right from one symbol variable that they already have set and it's why the
player dot config dot org because you are all underscore in coded underscore f m t underscore stream
the underscore Now
the guys type that.
I know that's really long but what that does is that gives us a comma separated list of the different
types of you are elves so different video formats and quality and stuff.
So what I'm going to do is we're actually going to split that when we run it so we can get an array
of each of you or else.
So I'm just going to click up on my keyboard get the last command back in the input field and then I'm
going to put split comma and here I've got these your elves here that read.
So in the file right here what we're going to do is we're going to basically just do that.
So var video you are owls is going to be equal to y t layer.
And it was y t player
config dot words dot you r l encoded f m t stream map and we're going to split it at the comma.
And this is going to be the video u r l.
It's going to return that object and then we're going to have to modify it further.