So you guys remember in one of the first
videos that we did in the HTML section I
I explained how the main difference
between a div element and a span element.
They are both generic, they're just used to
apply specific rules, and they're not
special elements like a header, you know.
And even the header doesn't apply a lot
of rules just to the header because it's
a header, but for instance in a element
does. It applies you know a text color,
and an underline, etc. And so a div, and a
span, and a header, and a main, and a section,
they're all generic. They generally have
the same rules applied by default with
the exception sometimes of block level
and inline display. So what we can do, we
can change block level elements to
inline. And how we do that,
so the h1 element is a block level, if I
hover over it here you're going to see
its full width, and if I change the
height, it actually does it, it changes
the height. So that's a very good
way of you know determining if an
item is block or inline. If it's block
it's going to be full width and you can
define the height, if it's inline you
cannot define the height. So what I'm
going to do is I'm going to change the
h1 element here to be inline instead of
block, and how we're going to do that in
my style sheet I'm going to target it,
open up the rule curly braces here, and
there's a property that you can set for
every single element. The property name
is display. And as you can see by this
pop-up, these are valid values for this
display attribute. So, by default the h1
is a block, but we can change it to inline. So
let's go ahead and change that, save it
and refresh, and what you're going to see
is that here it is not full width. If I change
the height it does not change it,
because it is now inline. Now there is
also a little, there's like a middle
way here, so we can change it to inline
block. Save and refresh, what you're going
to see is by default it is only as wide
as it has to be, but now you can add
height to it, as such. So inline blocks are
only as wide as they have to be but they
can use a height, block elements are full
width and can use height, and inline
elements are just like span elements, like
text here, they're just as high as
they have to be. So what I'm going to do
is I'm going to change this now, which is
the h3 element, I'm going to change that to
inline block as well. And how we're going
to do that is I'm going to put a comma
here and put h3. Now in CSS this means
any element that is either, that is
either an h1 or an h3 element apply this
rule to it, so it doesn't have to be both,
it needs to be either/or. So I'm going to
hit save and refresh, and we're going to
see that now they're on the same line.
Now something to note with this is that
the line height is going to become
important, because if the
line height is different, so for instance
if the text sizes are different, it's
going to stretch the entire line and
it's going to change where the smallest
element is placed. So, what we can do
there is we can add some margin, or we
can change the line height, or we can
even just change the height itself. So
let's hard limit this to height is 20
pixels, save it and refresh, and that
still didn't do it. So let's set margin
to zero pixels, save, refresh, now you'll
see that still they're not the correct
spacing. So I'm going to set line height now, and this applies to text,
it's for how high the line can be itself.
So we're going to set this to 20 pixels.
Save it,
refresh, and that still didn't really
align it, and it's because the baseline
here. Now how we would do this, if we
wanted to, and this is something that
I did previously but I didn't really
explain it that well because it
wasn't necessary at the time, we're going
to make this float. Erase all this, put it
back to normal, and then in just the h1
element I'm going to write float, and as
you can see these values for it, and I'm
going to say left. What this means when i
refresh is it's going to pull this to
the left of all the content, and any
content that can fit to the right of it
will. Now as you notice there are some
interesting things that will happen with
this. This, the background, is still all
the way over there because this element
technically exists there, but the content
of it will only begin whenever the right
side of this ends. So, I'm going to set
margin-left equal to 200 pixels. It needs to
be a bit more, 260. There we go. And then
padding off margin-top, 50 pixels. Now as
you'll see what happened there is the
margin of this has caused the floating
left element to go down as well. So with
the margin, as I explained in the
previous videos the orange there is the
margin, so you can set an overall margin
if we wanted all sides to be the same, we
would set margin just to one value, let's
say 10 pixels, and this would give it 10
pixels outside the element on all sides.
But,
you can also add margin, you can override
say one rule if you want, let's say margin-top,
let's set that twenty pixels. What will
happen now is the left bottom and right
sides will have a margin of ten pixels,
and the top will have a margin of 20
pixels, and again this means that the
element will begin within the confines
of that margin. So see the background of
that element, the white background
doesn't begin, it only fills the inside
space, the margin is considered outside
space. So this is good for spacing
elements away from each other, but if you
wanted to add more space between the
element and the content within the
element, what you're going to do is use
padding. I'm going to set this really big so
you guys can see, 50 pixels, there we
go. What happens now, as you can see with
the green, is that the padding exists
within the element, while the margin
exists outside of the element, and there
are times when you want to use either/or
and it might not be as obvious when
you're first looking at it, but there are
times when you might want to use padding
instead of margin, and we will definitely
get an opportunity to see that because
we're actually
going to be building a web site, and
padding and margin are two very, very
important parts of a website to properly
place elements.