Alright, welcome back guys. We are not
going to be talking about pseudo states
in this video, we're going to be doing
that in the next video, and the reason is
is because we're going to start, well
we're going to be talking about text
shadow, and that's the final text
property that I think we need
to focus on here.
So, let's go ahead and we're going to be
applying this rule to the body element,
and all inherited elements. So any child
element of the body is going to get a
text shadow as well. And as you can guess,
it's a two word property so it's
separated by a dash, text-shadow, and now
this is going to take a possible
four values that you pass in. The first
is the direction vertically, so let's say
2 pixels. The second is going to be the
distance from the text horizontally. The
third one is going to be a color. I'll save it
and refresh, sorry the first property
is left and right. I think I said that
one was up and down. So what we're going to be doing here, is that looks alright,
but the text shadow is not spread at all.
It's exactly the same weight and
thickness. So what we're going to do is
add a spread here, and we're going to set
that to 5 pixels as well, and it's going
to blur the text shadow and make it
actually look like a shadow. That's good.
We can set the previous two properties,
the first two, with a negative sign
that's going to move it in the opposite
direction. So, this one just defines the
gravity of the direction I guess, or the
anti-gravity, because it's the opposite.
Two pixels set as the first property
means two pixels to the right of the text,
negative five pixels means negative five
pixels down, right, so that would
obviously be five pixels up. That's
what's happened here.
I'm going to set these a little more
conservatively to both two pixels, and
refresh, that looks a little better. And
the spread I'm going to set that to 10
pixels just to spread it out a bit more.
Actually, no, what I'm going to do is
set these to one pixel, one pixel, and
then spread is going to be two pixels.
We're going to go really conservative
with this. And what you'll notice is the
the higher you set the spread, the
more it actually spreads it and lightens
it. You'll see here it's a light gray, but
if we only use a two pixel spread it's
going to be all condensed into those two
pixels. So what we're going to do is
we're going to set the color using
RGBA, and that way we can add alpha to it as well. And the reason we would do this
is because, we could totally set this to
a light gray color. So, I mean, that's too
light. Let's set it to ddd...it's a little bit
too light, let's set it to aaa,
there we go. We can kind of see that now.
What's going to happen, this works on a
white background because the text shadow
is between the text color and the
background. It looks like the background
is just darkened. Actually, I'm going to
set this quite low so we can get it a
little better. But what happens, let's say
I set the articles with a background of
red, what happens is the text shadow doesn't
account for that really, and it's still
dark. If I set this down to 000 you're
going to see that. Now setting the
property that way would work over here,
and it's really noticeable when we just
remove the spread all together. It's
still black rather than just
a darkened version. I mean, it's hard to see what I mean,
but you guys will encounter instances
where you see this. So what I'm going to do
is we're going to set this
with an RGBA color, I'm going to set it
to 0, 0, 0, and .3,
save it and refresh, and there is our
text shadow. It looks a bit better on all
different colored backgrounds. Let me get
that out of there. And along the same
lines are box shadows. So a box shadow is
kind of used in the same way to a text
shadow, but it's intended for elements
that aren't text, I guess. Not the internal
content, but rather the external content
or the element itself. So we're going to
set that on the articles, and we're going
to set box a shadow, and using the same
properties. The only difference is this
one can actually use, it can have a
maximum of five values instead of just
four. So, the first one is going to be the
left-right direction so let's say five
pixels, five pixels vertically, five pixel
spread, and then we're going to set the
color again to RGBA. Set that to
0, 0, 0, .6, and then we're going to end that line
with a semicolon,
and refresh, and there's our text shadow,
or there's our box shadow, rather. Now
what you can do is you can set this
value very low, and it's going to make it
less spread, obviously. Or you can set it
very high, that's not very high but
that's a bit higher, and you can make it
a bigger, softer shadow. I guess soft is
the term. But, what if you want the
spread that high and you want it still
very dense? What you can do is set a
fourth property which is also in pixels,
and this changes
the density of the shadow. So if we now set this to two pixels, third property rather
two pixels, this controls how far the
shadow outreach is, while this is I
guess the softness. So let's set that back to
20, this back to set it to negative one,
let's refresh, and there we've got box
shadows that look alright. Now, this is
when the RGBA color for this is
going to make sense, I'm going to set
this to .2, and we've got a very,
very light hint of shadow there. Let me
increase that to .3 actually, that's a
little bit better. There you go.
Now in the next video we're talking about
pseudo states, this is going to become
really relevant because we're going to
be mixing pseudo states with these box
shadows.