Alright, so, in this video what we're
going to be doing is learning about ways
that we can then use the variables that
we create to do certain things. So, I'm
going to create a variable here called
isPremiumUser. So, we start with the var
keyword and then we call it is premium
user, and this is going to be false. So,
here what we're going to do is we're
going to create an if statement that
basically determines you know if this is
true then do this, if it is false then do
that. So, what you do to create an if
statement you write the word if, and then
brackets, and you open and close them. And here is where you put your comparison
statement. So, just like in the previous
video we're going to say if(isPremiumUser
== true) we're going to open up
curly brackets and space it like that. So,
the syntax of this is the if keyword,
opening bracket, and then your comparison,
and then your closing bracket, and then
you open curly bracket, and you can close
the curly bracket, and all the code
that's going to run if that statement
equals true is going to be written in
here. So, for this instance what we're
going to do is just console.log("Thanks
for being a loyal customer!"). I'm going to
save it, and when I refresh this
nothing's printed out because I'm not a
premium user. If I change premium user to true and save it and refresh, then it
says Thanks for being a loyal customer!
Again, if I change it to false, it's not
going to do that. Now, if you're always
checking just what is true you don't
even have to put this part.
It's going to do a basic comparison right
off the bat to check if the variable is you
know if it exists and has a value, and if
it doesn't, and we can basically
shorthand this. If we're checking if
something is true, we can erase all that
and just type if and then the variable
that would either hold true or false. In
this case it holds false so it's not
going to do anything, but if I write true
here, save it, it's going to do this. Now,
this will work if a variable exists. So
if I create a string that says
false inside of it, and refresh, it still
prints that out because it's basically
saying if is premium user and it exists,
it has string, so it equals to true.
We're going to leave this false actually
and down here after we do the if
statement you can do an else statement,
and directly after the closing curly
bracket here just write the keyword else,
and then open up a new set of curly
brackets. And now this is going to be run
if is premium user is not true. So I'm
going to write this out the long way
just to simplify things here. So, if
(isPremiumUser == true) that's
going to do this bit of code, else it's
going to run this. So, console.log("You
should subscribe to our premium service.")
Save it and refresh, where it is false we
see you should subscribe to our premium
service because we've set these premium
user to false. So, what's happening is
saying if premium user then do whatever
is in here, so the compiler or the
interpreter, doesn't even parse
this code here if it is not true. It says
if this is true then do this, but if it's
not then run this. So, for instance, we
could put a variable in here that
doesn't exist, and it wouldn't freak out
or anything because it's not even
parsing this code. But, if we set this to
true it's gonna freak out
because it's going to say it's not
defined, we don't we haven't defined this.
So, that was just to show you guys
basically that it only reads I guess
what it needs to. I guess that's the
easiest way to say it. Now, we're going to
create another variable and we're going
to learn about else if, so if else if
else. It's going to make a lot more sense
once I write this out, so just bear with
me. var myAge is going to be equal to
28; So, what we can do is we're going to
create an if statement, and the
comparison here is going to be equal to,
or less than rather. So, if(myAge) is less
than 1 we're going to open up our curly
brackets, and we're going to
console.log("You are a baby.") Then what
we're going to do here instead of just
writing else and then opening up curly
braces which is kind of like a catch-all,
we're going to write else space if, and
we follow the same format. So, myAge is
less than 3, open up your curly brackets,
and we're going to print out console.log
("You are a toddler.")
And we're going to do this a few more
times, so get into practice of it. I'm
going to walk you through a few more
times just to make sure that we covered it,
and very well. So, after the closing curly
bracket of the previous step, you're
going to write else if, you're going to
open up your brackets, myAge is less
than 10. We're going to say "You're a big
kid." else if(myAge) is less than 19,
actually we're going to say less than or
equal to in this instance because 19 is
a teenager, and we're going to print out
"You are a teenager." And, we're going to do
two more, so else if(myAge) is less than
40, we're going to say "You are an adult."
else console.log("You must be old, you're
not in our records."). Save it, and then I'm
going to run this. It's going to print
out that I am an adult. So what happens
here, it might look that my age is
greater...so it's not less than 40 and it's
not you know else, what I'm going to do
is change my age to 4. I'm going to save it, refresh, and it says you're a big kid even though my
age is less than 10 which is the
condition it's capturing here. It's also
less than 19, but it's not printing this
out, and my age is also less than 40 and
it's not printing this out, and this is
because it stops at the first one where
the statement returns true. So, in this
instance it says is my age less than
one? No, okay, move on. Is my age less than three? No, move on. Is my age less than ten?
Yes! So, what's between these curly brackets?
And then it reads that and it prints it
out, and then it stops. It doesn't parse
any of this after that. So, you're
going to have to write these in a
certain way so that they make sense.
There are instances where if you write
it the wrong way the wrong thing is
going to happen, and I'm going to try and
think of an example before I start the
next video so that I can show you what
not to do, so that you're always going to
be writing these correctly. So that's an if
statement, and how to do a very basic one to check if something is true or false
which we're comparing an equal sign. So,
then we also compare an integer to
hard coded integers. This is something
that you don't want to do. You don't want
to ever do it backwards. If one is
greater than my age print out you're a
baby. Meaning that this would return true
if my age is anything less than one, but
this is written backwards. We
call this Yoda code because in Star Wars
Yoda talks backwards. So, you never want
to write it like this, you always want to...
you're going to compare something to
something. So the thing that we're
comparing is my age that always goes on
the left. So, yeah, that's if statements
and else if and else, we're going to be
learning more about these types of loops,
or conditional statements we call them,
or rather just bigger chunks of code,
that's a better way to put it. We're
going to be covering that more in the
next video.