Alright, so, how do we make things round? Well, that's a great question, and it's
not really, I mean it's kind of relevant
because you can still use it for a lot
of things, but round web design is
something from the early 2000s and we're
gonna stay away from that as much as
possible, which means hard corners or
a very small amount of roundness on the
corners. And so what I'm gonna start
working with is the input here, let's say
I want to have slightly rounded corners
on this input. I'm gonna use the border-radius property, and if you only
supply one value to this property
it affects all the corners. So I'm gonna
say three pixels. Save it and refresh, and
now when we set the border radius we
also need to set the border to fix the
fact that it's reverting to an older
state. So let's set border one pixel
solid, sort of a gray color, there we go.
So there's our rounded corners and you
might not be able to see them that well,
so I'm gonna make them bigger. Let's go
with ten pixel border radius, and this is
gonna make them quite round. Now this
reminds me of the search input field
on Twitter. I'm not sure if it still
looks like that but it used to a long
time ago, and Facebook as well. Things
have straightened out quite a bit in web
design, so I'm not sure if this is still
the state of those things, but that's how
to use border radius, in a nutshell.
Usually if you're going to be making
anything round, or the edges of something
round, you're going to be
applying it to all sides. Now you don't
need a border for the border radius to
work. So I'm going to
this to transparent. And that's another
thing, transparent is a valid color. It's
not a hex color or RGBA so you're not
you know putting it in any specific
format, it's the word, it's a key word,
you're just gonna type transparent. This
will apply to setting the background
color of something, setting the color of
the text if you really want to, but
that's up to you. I'm gonna save this and
refresh, and now you'll see there's no
border, but when I click into it we still
have the border apply there. So I'm
actually gonna remove that. Focus let's
say just remove that all together.
Save it, refresh it, and there you
go. You can see the border radius still
affects this even without a border, so
it's basically the element itself. It's
kind of like an element radius, but I
guess we call it a border radius. Now,
reset that border so that we can see what
we're doing here. I'm gonna supply it two
arguments 10 pixels and then 20 pixels,
and what you'll see is it's kind of
offset. So the top left becomes the 10
pixels, the top right becomes 20 pixels,
the bottom right becomes 20 pixels, or the bottom left, and the
bottom right is 10, and so think of it
like counter, or clockwise. So we're
setting 10, 20, 10, 20. That's how
that works. Now you can also supply four
arguments. So on the second one I'm going to say two pixels, and then the last one
it's gonna be really big at fifty
pixels so that we can really see which
side it effects. So as you can see, this
is 10, 20, 5, and 50. It's a clockwise circle
that you're going around when you're
defining these. Now, something else that is
going to confuse things, and we need to
do it on a bigger element so we're gonna
be doing it on the on the image here,
let's use the image, yeah we're going to
use the image there. So, you can set two,
you can set each corner to have its own
border radius property, and you can set
two values if you're doing it that way.
So the image right here, I need to go
find out how we should target that, it's
not an image it's a class of article
image right there. So I'm gonna jump over
to my stylesheet and target the class
article-image, it's gonna work really
well if I spell it correctly. What we're
gonna say is border-top-left-radius, and
again it's CSS so every word is
separated by a dash and it's all lowercase.
border-top-left-radius, you can do
border-top-right-radius, border-bottom-left-radius,
etc. So I'm gonna set first just one value in
here so you guys can see what happens. As you can probably assume, it's just going
to change that one border radius, but
we're going to apply two values here, and
what's gonna happen is the first one is
the top edge, yeah first one
is the top edge right about to the
corner itself, and then the second value
is the left edge. See it kind of bends
here and then it gets more gradual, and
that's supplying two arguments to it. Now
let's set it even bigger. Now you can see
it really well.
So, if we were going from the center of
the element to the corner it would be
about here, and so you can see on the
left hand side it's starting to, I think I
set it to 20 pixels or 50 pixels, so
it's doing a 50 pixel border radius,
and it gets here and it's like oh, let's
switch to 100, and it gets more
gradual as it goes. I can't think of any
point this specific application would be
relevant, especially in web design where
things are getting more straight edged
and hard corners, but if you ever feel
like using this that's how to use two
values in each border radius declaration.
Now one final thing, you can easily make
something that has equal width and
height a circle. So what I'm going to do is this
article image right here, I'm going to
set it to height 200 pixels and width
200 pixels, and then I'm going to set
border radius 100%. Save it
and refresh, and what happens is it
becomes a full circle because each of
these edges I guess begin to turn right
towards the other point where it can
then you know create a radius to the
next point, and it keeps going. So that's
100%, but you can also set
it to a full pixel, 100 pixel. Save it,
refresh, and it's still going to be a
circle, and that's because the width and
height is 200, so we could actually split
it down to 50 pixels, and that's 1/4, and
it should...no, sorry, 100 because it's half the height and then half the width, and
that's exactly what we're working with
to get it from this point right here, to
the top point, that's 100 pixels up and a
100 pixels right, so it's a 100
pixels. So that's border radius, that's
gonna be fun, and using circles to make
an element circular, that's when the
border radius is most used, at least by
me. I don't really make things rounded
that much, but we'll get more into that
later. In the next video, I think we
should cover pseudo elements. So kind of
like pseudo states they're not real
elements, but they're kind of real.