Alright guys. So we've already learned
about a lot of different elements, and
I'm sure that's a lot of information
that you're going to have to find a way
to retain. For the most part, the
syntax is really easy to learn when
it comes to CSS and HTML. It's the
specifics that you really need to
practice. Which specific elements like
a video element, a div, a span, and then also
CSS properties or attributes, and that's
border-bottom, or position, as seen here.
Those are the things that you're going
to need to really hammer away on in
order to retain all this information. So,
with that set and out of the way, there's
a gray area here where an element
doesn't really exist, but we can make it
exist if we want to, and that's before
and after. So, the main header here, it has
a before and after, there's a partial
element before it and an element after
it, and they're not visible, and they're not
used unless we actually use it ourselves.
So let's go ahead and say main-header,
we're gonna put two colons, and gonna say
before. Now this creates a blank element
that didn't exist before now, it has no
default styles, it has no properties
assigned by default, so that's where we
need to start defining the content. So,
content is a property that we're
generally not going to use except for
right here, and it's going to be blank,
and this just tells it that it has
content so it can be displayed, and then
we're gonna set display to block. Save
this and refresh the page, and you won't
notice any difference because we haven't
applied styles to it, but when I drop
this down here you're now gonna see a
little before. It has no width, no height, or
it's actually full width because we set
display to block. If we didn't, it would
be 0 by 0. And if we set the content to
none, if I
disable that altogether, it's just gonna
go away. It just disappears. It needs to
have the content property set, you can
even put text in here if you want. We can
save it and refresh and there,
we've got content in it, you can see it.
But we don't want content in it, normally
you're not going to you, normally this is
going to be used to further style in the
first, beginning there. So let's say,
or it's gonna be further defining styles
for this element, it's just going to
create an additional element that you
can position differently. So let's say to
the left of that text I want to have a
box that's 5 pixels wide and 80
pixels high. So what I'm gonna do is I'm
going to set the width to, did I say 10
pixels? And then the height to 80 pixels,
save it and refresh, and again nothing
happens except you know it pushes
everything down, but you can't see
it itself yet. So here's where we're
gonna define the background. In this
instance, it's going to be black. We just
want to create a black rectangle to the
left. Well, that kind of screwed that up,
but that's where we use positioning. So
this is when absolute positioning should
be used. You're gonna set the position to
absolute, and then I'm gonna refresh, oh
the whole header is only 80 pixels high.
I thought it was 100. Let me change this
to take off 10 on both the top and
bottom, so the height of the before
pseudo-element now is gonna be 60 pixels,
there we go. We can actually go even
shorter. Let's go with 40 and see what that
looks like. And now with
positioning, with absolute positioning,
and here's where I'm gonna start to use
the console actually or the dev tools,
I'm going to select that, and I'm going
to start adding styles to it through
here. Writing CSS directly in the
developer tools is essentially the same
process as writing it within the actual
CSS file, except you don't have to keep
going back and forth if you're playing
around with something. So, what I'm gonna
do is I'm going to set margin-top to 20
pixels, and I'm gonna hover over it, and you
can see on the very top there, see the
orange space that it created, that's
using margin to do what we want, and
that's technically part of that element.
Although, it's unstyled. So what we're
gonna do instead is we're going to set
top to 20 pixels. As you can see, it didn't
move it, so it keeps it in the same
position as a 20 pixel margin did, except
now it does not become part of the
element. So, this is an absolute
positioning property, so it's left, right,
and bottom. So what I'm gonna do is I'm
going to set left to a 100 pixels,
and you'll see that it moved it over
here. Now if I remove the top rule here,
and the left, I'm gonna say a bottom is
equal to zero, and what this does is it
moves it to the bottom of its element.
I mean, I guess you can look at it like
this is a child element of header,
although it's not child element, it's
it's inside the header element, so this
is the container of it, but it's not a
child, I guess. It gets a little confusing
there. But, you can position it you know
left, and bottom, and top, and stuff, and
let's change the color so that we can
see the text underneath it, and you'll
see that it
defaults to, I mean we haven't applied any depth here. We've been working in two
dimensions so far, and that's the
horizontal and vertical, or the X and the
y-axis. But, we haven't even talked about
the z-axis and I think we should do that
in the next video, I don't think we
should do that right now, but that's, this
I guess it segues into that. So let's
stop here and in the next video let's
talk about depth.