Alright guys. So what we're going to be
learning about in this video is just how
to put images into a webpage, and it's
important to note that images or image
tags are block level, which means they're
going to appear full width within the page.
So, for our news article here I've
downloaded some images. I've downloaded a
dog, chocolate, and HTML 5 from Google, and these are going to be corresponding to
each article, as you can see here. So, each
article is going to have it's own image.
So what we're going to do is jump up to
the top one here, and the image should be
above the title. Within the article
we're going to go ahead and type img. Now
this is self closing. That's all you need
to do to create an image element, but as
you'll see there's no image inside of it
and that's because there's an essential
property here, or attribute of the
element, which is src. And this basically
is an abbreviation for the word source.
So we need the source of the image that
we want to show here, and that is a file
path. Now if it's within the same
directory you don't have to worry about
anything just type the name of
the file. So in this case it's dog.jpg, save it refresh, and there we go.
There's the picture of our dog. Let's go
ahead and create one for the second
article which is about chocolate in
outer space. So the source for this one
is going to be chocolate.jpg, but what
you can do is, if you want, if it's in the
same directory, and this is going to be
relevant sometimes, if it's in the same
directory at the same path you can use
just the title. And once we get into
rewriting and stuff for URLs, which might
not even be in this course, you're going
to have to reference the current
directory that this page is in, so that's
./ So, it's chocolate.jpg, and then we close it. As you can see,
new study confirms chocolate is in space,
Mars bar, which is fitting. And then
finally we have the html5 article, and so
the source in this one...we can see
the source to our project, so we're going
to put an absolute source here. So,
C:\Users\nickg\Projects\web-course
and then the file name which is
html5.png, and then self close that. And we see here this is actually pretty big, so
what I need to do is I need to set the
width of this to a 100%, or
any pixel size we could also do. But by
setting it to a hundred percent it's just
going to make it only be as wide as the
page, but then it's also going to scale
it proportionally so that it won't be
stretched or anything, it will then
become as tall as it needs to be to fit
the width that we've specified. And so
that is the image tag and how to add it
to your web page.
These are block elements but you can do
crafty things like making them up here
inline, and we're going to be getting
into that with CSS.