Alright guys. So, we've got a mostly
working form here with very basic
functionality. What we're going to be
doing is adding in a way for the user to
select a size. So under the address here,
let me move these lines here so I can
get both of those line breaks above
where I'm going to create the size, I'm going to
create an h4 element as a title so we
can know what this refers to. It's going
to be Size. So we open it, type stuff,
close it, and now we're going to create a
select attribute or element. And what
this is it's multiple choice in a
drop-down that people can select one of.
So it's kind of like a radio element
except it displays in a drop-down. You
can also select multiple in a select box,
and that's not really pertinent to what
we're doing here. So just learning the
select box that's what it does. So we're
going to give it a name and the name is
going to be size, and that's all we need
to do. So let's go ahead and close this
select element. I'm going to save it and
refresh here, and you'll see that it
drops down but there's nothing in it yet
because we haven't put anything in it. So
that's what we're going to be learning
now. Within a select element which lets
you select items from a drop-down we
need to have options, and so the next
element we're going to learn is very
appropriately named option. And each
option is going to have a property of
value and this is going to be what the
option is. So we're going to start off
with 12-inch, and let's put the cost
there too. Let's say
$13.99...I'm not sure if that's expensive
or not, but it's good pizza. So, the next
one is going to be 16 inches, and just so
you guys can see better the format of it
you open it, and you never
put an attribute in the closing tag,
I guess that's important to know, you
only ever put attributes within the
opening tag itself. So we're going to say
16 inch and we're going to say that is
going to be $16.99. On the next line, and we don't need to add line breaks or
anything it's all automatic here within
the select list, we're going to create
another one with a value of 18, and we're
going to type out what's going to appear
as the option, and this is going to be
$19.99. And then just in case anybody's
really hungry, we need to add a very
large option and this is going to be 72
inches, and the price for that is going
to be $149.99. Alright, so, with our
select box created and four options
within it, I'm going to save this and
refresh, and there we go.
So we've got our select box there. It's
going to let people choose a size. So
right now this is basically feature
complete as what it's intended to do on
the front end. We give the user the
option of delivery or pickup. If they
choose delivery they need to add in
their address, maybe their phone number
as well. We let them choose a size of a
pizza, and then also ingredients. These
are all the important things about
ordering a pizza. These are the things
you need to be able to do. So what we're
going to do now, we're ready for it, we
just need to let them
send it to us. So we're going to create a
button with a type submit, and it's
going to say Place Order, and we're going
to close that button. I'm going to save
it here, and then refresh, I need to add a
line break above that. It doesn't look quite
right, I'm going to add two of them actually.
There we go. So now what we're able to do
is we're able to select a few different
ones, and then hit place order. As you can
see, I've made this a get method up in
the form here, the method is equal to get,
and so what it does is it carries across
all these values as you know in the in
the URL. So this is how they're going to
be accessed within PHP. If you wanted to
automate this a bit, I mean this is
why you would use get. If you want to
send someone directly to a page and send
parameters to that page as well, you're
going to use this. So if I sent you a
link like this it would automatically order
you a pizza at my address. So, that's how
the get method works. And post, just so you
guys can see, go back here and refresh.
I'm going to place our order again, I'm going
to hit place order, and it sends it to
the place order script without the URL.
So it's all done behind the scenes, and
that's why you would use the post method
for sensitive data like passwords, or
address, stuff like that. So that is our
form and basically that's complete,
except for one final touch and we're
going to add that in the next video.